Tina Cai

UX/UI DESIGNER

CONTACT

Seattle, WA, USA

(206) 407-4205

🖔 tinacai.me

(in) in/tinacai97

SKILLS

Research

Competitor analysis, user interviews, usability testing, user flows, user journeys, persona development

Design

Information architecture, sketching, wireframing, rapid prototyping, UI design, mobile design, web design, accessibile design

Software

Figma, Sketch, Adobe XD, PhotoShop, Miro, InVision, Marvel, Jira, VSCode, GitHub, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React

EDUCATION

Product Design Certificate

MAR 2022 - MAY 2022

Co.Lab, Cohort #10
Design Buddies Scholarship

User Experience Design Certificate

MAY 2021 - JAN 2022

CareerFoundry
Front-End Specialization

B.S. in Electrical & Computer Engineering

SEP 2015 - JUN 2019

University of Washington, Seattle Power Design Concentration

ABOUT

I am a UX/UI designer with experience in front-end development and engineering. I combine my newly-found creative and well-practiced analytical mindset to craft experiences with and for people. When not designing, find me playing video games, baking, or practicing pilates

EXPERIENCE

UX Design Specialist

STARTING JAN 2023

SAP

• Joining the SAP Next Talent Program as part of the design track

UX/UI Designer (Contract)

JUN 2022 - DEC 2022

Rowy

- Re-designed the authentication and onboarding process given strict external constraints, seeing a 15% increase in user sign up completion
- Designed new navigation, subscription, demo, and other upcoming features for both the Rowy product and website

Graduate Engineer

JAN 2020 - APR 2021

Arup

- Designed building power systems based on client and team needs, producing 100+ design deliverables across 13 unique projects
- Social Committee Lead and Connect Women Co-lead

Engineering Intern

JUN 2019 - SEP 2019

Katerra

 Cross-checked engineering designs based on building owner and team needs, resulting in a design package of 80+ code compliant drawings for a multi-building apartment complex

Engineering Intern

JUN 2018 - SEP 2018

City of Tacoma

- Designed power systems for new residential homes, helping 20+ projects move forward in construction
- Performed site visits to communicate with customers, form feasible solutions for new projects, and facilitate existing project builds

PROJECTS

Mesh

MAR 2022 - MAY 2022

[tinacai.me/mesh.html]

- Worked alongside a product manager and developer to design and ship a solution that empowers early-career tech talent to network
- Took responsibility of product HTML documentation and CSS styling to assist development team and ship proposed MVP on time

Personal Design Portfolio

NOV 2021 - FEB 2022

[tinacai.me]

 Designed and hand-developed an online portfolio to showcase design case studies and practice front-end development